Justice B-PERSON
Sunita I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

The O
court O
examined O
Article B-LAW
14 I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Justice B-PERSON
Neha I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
judgment. O

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Civil O
Appeal O
No. O
3456/2023. O

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Criminal O
Appeal O
No. O
9876/2022. O

Justice B-PERSON
Anil I-PERSON
Gupta I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

The O
matter O
was O
listed O
before O
Kerala B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court. I-ORG

Advocate B-PERSON
Deepak I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
submitted O
written O
arguments. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Deepak I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Deepak I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Nisha I-PERSON
Kapoor I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

The O
court O
examined O
Motor B-LAW
Vehicles I-LAW
Act I-LAW
1988 I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Justice B-PERSON
Vikram I-PERSON
Desai I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

The O
matter O
was O
listed O
before O
Karnataka B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court. I-ORG

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Section B-LAW
420 I-LAW
of I-LAW
the I-LAW
Indian I-LAW
Penal I-LAW
Code. I-LAW

The O
matter O
was O
listed O
before O
Kerala B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court. I-ORG

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Criminal O
Writ O
No. O
4567/2024. O

Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of I-ORG
India I-ORG
delivered O
its O
judgment O
on O
3rd B-DATE
February I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Advocate B-PERSON
Deepak I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
25th B-DATE
August I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Neha I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
25th B-DATE
August I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Ramesh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
7th B-DATE
April I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Vikram I-PERSON
Desai I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Suresh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
submitted O
written O
arguments. O

Justice B-PERSON
Rajiv I-PERSON
Malhotra I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
3rd B-DATE
February I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Justice B-PERSON
Meera I-PERSON
Reddy I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Justice B-PERSON
Meera I-PERSON
Reddy I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Justice B-PERSON
Rajiv I-PERSON
Malhotra I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Justice B-PERSON
Priya I-PERSON
Sharma I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Justice B-PERSON
Priya I-PERSON
Sharma I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
22nd B-DATE
January I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Writ O
Petition O
No. O
5678/2024. O

Justice B-PERSON
Sunita I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
judgment. O

Justice B-PERSON
Meera I-PERSON
Reddy I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
10th B-DATE
September I-DATE
2022. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Anil I-PERSON
Gupta I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
25th B-DATE
August I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Advocate B-PERSON
Pooja I-PERSON
Agarwal I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Section B-LAW
376 I-LAW
IPC. I-LAW

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
15th B-DATE
March I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

The O
court O
examined O
Motor B-LAW
Vehicles I-LAW
Act I-LAW
1988 I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Nisha I-PERSON
Kapoor I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Suresh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
submitted O
written O
arguments. O

Justice B-PERSON
Kavita I-PERSON
Rao I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
18th B-DATE
November I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Meera I-PERSON
Reddy I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Justice B-PERSON
Ramesh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
25th B-DATE
August I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
3rd B-DATE
February I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Priya I-PERSON
Sharma I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
5th B-DATE
May I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Criminal O
Appeal O
No. O
9876/2022. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Anjali I-PERSON
Khanna I-PERSON
submitted O
written O
arguments. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Nisha I-PERSON
Kapoor I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Justice B-PERSON
Rajiv I-PERSON
Malhotra I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Motor B-LAW
Vehicles I-LAW
Act I-LAW
1988. I-LAW

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Civil O
Appeal O
No. O
3456/2023. O

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Sanjay I-PERSON
Dubey I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

The O
court O
examined O
Consumer B-LAW
Protection I-LAW
Act I-LAW
2019 I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Justice B-PERSON
Priya I-PERSON
Sharma I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

The O
court O
examined O
Section B-LAW
302 I-LAW
IPC I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
22nd B-DATE
January I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Kavita I-PERSON
Rao I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
10th B-DATE
September I-DATE
2022. I-DATE

The O
court O
examined O
Consumer B-LAW
Protection I-LAW
Act I-LAW
2019 I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Justice B-PERSON
Vikram I-PERSON
Desai I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Case O
No. O
ABC/2023. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Karthik I-PERSON
Iyer I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Justice B-PERSON
Vikram I-PERSON
Desai I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
12th B-DATE
December I-DATE
2022. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Rajiv I-PERSON
Malhotra I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Suresh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Criminal O
Writ O
No. O
4567/2024. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Article B-LAW
14. I-LAW

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Case O
No. O
12345/2023. O

Justice B-PERSON
Ramesh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
20th B-DATE
October I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Sunita I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Suresh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Justice B-PERSON
Vikram I-PERSON
Desai I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Motor B-LAW
Vehicles I-LAW
Act I-LAW
1988. I-LAW

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Motor B-LAW
Vehicles I-LAW
Act I-LAW
1988. I-LAW

Justice B-PERSON
Anil I-PERSON
Gupta I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
5th B-DATE
May I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Criminal O
Writ O
No. O
4567/2024. O

The O
court O
examined O
Section B-LAW
376 I-LAW
IPC I-LAW
in O
detail. O

The O
petitioner O
cited O
Consumer B-LAW
Protection I-LAW
Act I-LAW
2019 I-LAW
in O
the O
arguments. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Civil O
Appeal O
No. O
3456/2023. O

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Criminal O
Writ O
No. O
4567/2024. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Article B-LAW
14. I-LAW

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
10th B-DATE
September I-DATE
2022. I-DATE

The O
matter O
was O
listed O
before O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of I-ORG
India. I-ORG

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
PIL O
No. O
1234/2022. O

The O
court O
examined O
Section B-LAW
302 I-LAW
IPC I-LAW
in O
detail. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Civil O
Appeal O
No. O
3456/2023. O

Justice B-PERSON
Vikram I-PERSON
Desai I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
12th B-DATE
December I-DATE
2022. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Meera I-PERSON
Reddy I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
15th B-DATE
March I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

The O
court O
examined O
Section B-LAW
302 I-LAW
IPC I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Justice B-PERSON
Ramesh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Justice B-PERSON
Ramesh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
18th B-DATE
November I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Neha I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
judgment. O

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Case O
No. O
12345/2023. O

The O
court O
examined O
Article B-LAW
21 I-LAW
of I-LAW
the I-LAW
Constitution I-LAW
of I-LAW
India I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Deepak I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
submitted O
written O
arguments. O

The O
petitioner O
cited O
Section B-LAW
420 I-LAW
of I-LAW
the I-LAW
Indian I-LAW
Penal I-LAW
Code I-LAW
in O
the O
arguments. O

The O
matter O
was O
listed O
before O
Delhi B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court. I-ORG

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Companies B-LAW
Act I-LAW
2013. I-LAW

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Suresh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Justice B-PERSON
Neha I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
judgment. O

Justice B-PERSON
Anil I-PERSON
Gupta I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Justice B-PERSON
Ramesh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

The O
petitioner O
cited O
Consumer B-LAW
Protection I-LAW
Act I-LAW
2019 I-LAW
in O
the O
arguments. O

Justice B-PERSON
Priya I-PERSON
Sharma I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

The O
court O
examined O
Section B-LAW
302 I-LAW
IPC I-LAW
in O
detail. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Criminal O
Appeal O
No. O
9876/2022. O

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Madras B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court I-ORG
delivered O
its O
judgment O
on O
22nd B-DATE
January I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Motor B-LAW
Vehicles I-LAW
Act I-LAW
1988. I-LAW

Advocate B-PERSON
Pooja I-PERSON
Agarwal I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Companies B-LAW
Act I-LAW
2013. I-LAW

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Suresh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Justice B-PERSON
Sunita I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
judgment. O

Justice B-PERSON
Anil I-PERSON
Gupta I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Civil O
Appeal O
No. O
3456/2023. O

Justice B-PERSON
Neha I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
judgment. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Article B-LAW
32. I-LAW

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Civil O
Appeal O
No. O
3456/2023. O

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
25th B-DATE
August I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Meera I-PERSON
Reddy I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

The O
matter O
was O
listed O
before O
Calcutta B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court. I-ORG

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Criminal O
Writ O
No. O
4567/2024. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Section B-LAW
420 I-LAW
of I-LAW
the I-LAW
Indian I-LAW
Penal I-LAW
Code. I-LAW

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Justice B-PERSON
Anil I-PERSON
Gupta I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
7th B-DATE
April I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Writ O
Petition O
No. O
5678/2024. O

Justice B-PERSON
Rajiv I-PERSON
Malhotra I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Section B-LAW
498A I-LAW
IPC. I-LAW

Justice B-PERSON
Rajiv I-PERSON
Malhotra I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
7th B-DATE
April I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Kavita I-PERSON
Rao I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
22nd B-DATE
January I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Sanjay I-PERSON
Dubey I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Deepak I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
submitted O
written O
arguments. O

The O
court O
examined O
Article B-LAW
21 I-LAW
of I-LAW
the I-LAW
Constitution I-LAW
of I-LAW
India I-LAW
in O
detail. O

The O
counsel O
relied O
on O
Article B-LAW
32. I-LAW

Justice B-PERSON
Priya I-PERSON
Sharma I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
25th B-DATE
August I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Ramesh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
25th B-DATE
August I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Neha I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
12th B-DATE
December I-DATE
2022. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Rajiv I-PERSON
Malhotra I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Deepak I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
submitted O
written O
arguments. O

The O
petitioner O
cited O
Consumer B-LAW
Protection I-LAW
Act I-LAW
2019 I-LAW
in O
the O
arguments. O

Justice B-PERSON
Kavita I-PERSON
Rao I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
judgment. O

Justice B-PERSON
Neha I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
12th B-DATE
December I-DATE
2022. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
18th B-DATE
November I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Justice B-PERSON
Vikram I-PERSON
Desai I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
3rd B-DATE
February I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Case O
No. O
ABC/2023. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Deepak I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
submitted O
written O
arguments. O

The O
matter O
was O
listed O
before O
Karnataka B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court. I-ORG

The O
court O
examined O
Article B-LAW
21 I-LAW
of I-LAW
the I-LAW
Constitution I-LAW
of I-LAW
India I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Karthik I-PERSON
Iyer I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Advocate B-PERSON
Pooja I-PERSON
Agarwal I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Justice B-PERSON
Vikram I-PERSON
Desai I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
20th B-DATE
October I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Rajiv I-PERSON
Malhotra I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Justice B-PERSON
Priya I-PERSON
Sharma I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Criminal O
Writ O
No. O
4567/2024. O

Allahabad B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court I-ORG
delivered O
its O
judgment O
on O
22nd B-DATE
January I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Justice B-PERSON
Ramesh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Case O
No. O
12345/2023. O

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Suresh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of I-ORG
India I-ORG
delivered O
its O
judgment O
on O
22nd B-DATE
January I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

The O
court O
examined O
Section B-LAW
302 I-LAW
IPC I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Justice B-PERSON
Neha I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
judgment. O

Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of I-ORG
India I-ORG
delivered O
its O
judgment O
on O
20th B-DATE
October I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
10th B-DATE
September I-DATE
2022. I-DATE

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
20th B-DATE
October I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

The O
matter O
was O
listed O
before O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of I-ORG
India. I-ORG

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
25th B-DATE
August I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

The O
court O
examined O
Article B-LAW
21 I-LAW
of I-LAW
the I-LAW
Constitution I-LAW
of I-LAW
India I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Sanjay I-PERSON
Dubey I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Justice B-PERSON
Rajiv I-PERSON
Malhotra I-PERSON
presided O
over O
the O
hearing. O

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
18th B-DATE
November I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

The O
petitioner O
cited O
Section B-LAW
420 I-LAW
of I-LAW
the I-LAW
Indian I-LAW
Penal I-LAW
Code I-LAW
in O
the O
arguments. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Writ O
Petition O
No. O
5678/2024. O

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
12th B-DATE
December I-DATE
2022. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Meera I-PERSON
Reddy I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
25th B-DATE
August I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Case O
No. O
12345/2023. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Special O
Leave O
Petition O
No. O
7890/2024. O

Bombay B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court I-ORG
delivered O
its O
judgment O
on O
22nd B-DATE
January I-DATE
2023. I-DATE

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Suresh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Justice B-PERSON
Sunita I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
judgment. O

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Patel I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
15th B-DATE
March I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Anil I-PERSON
Gupta I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
5th B-DATE
May I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Criminal O
Writ O
No. O
4567/2024. O

Justice B-PERSON
Kavita I-PERSON
Rao I-PERSON
observed O
the O
legal O
provisions. O

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
3rd B-DATE
February I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Case O
No. O
ABC/2023. O

The O
matter O
was O
listed O
before O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of I-ORG
India. I-ORG

Advocate B-PERSON
Deepak I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Suresh I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
submitted O
written O
arguments. O

Proceedings O
commenced O
on O
15th B-DATE
March I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Justice B-PERSON
Neha I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
heard O
the O
matter O
on O
7th B-DATE
April I-DATE
2024. I-DATE

Senior B-PERSON
Advocate I-PERSON
Sanjay I-PERSON
Dubey I-PERSON
represented O
the O
defendant. O

The O
court O
examined O
Consumer B-LAW
Protection I-LAW
Act I-LAW
2019 I-LAW
in O
detail. O

Reference O
was O
made O
to O
Criminal O
Writ O
No. O
4567/2024. O

The O
case O
was O
filed O
as O
Criminal O
Writ O
No. O
4567/2024. O

The O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of I-ORG
India I-ORG
dismissed O
the O
appeal O
in O
Case B-CASE
No. I-CASE
1245 I-CASE
/ I-CASE
2021 I-CASE
. O

Justice B-PERSON
Amit I-PERSON
Sharma I-PERSON
delivered O
the O
judgment O
on O
15th B-DATE
March I-DATE
2022 I-DATE
. O

The O
High B-ORG
Court I-ORG
of I-ORG
Delhi I-ORG
heard O
the O
matter O
. O

The O
respondent O
was O
represented O
by O
Mr. B-PERSON
Rajesh I-PERSON
Verma I-PERSON
. O

The O
court O
referred O
to O
Section B-LAW
302 I-LAW
of O
the O
Indian B-LAW
Penal I-LAW
Code I-LAW
. O

The O
FIR O
was O
registered O
as O
FIR B-CASE
No. I-CASE
112 I-CASE
/ I-CASE
2020 I-CASE
. O

The O
judgment O
in O
State B-ORG
v. O
Kumar B-PERSON
was O
cited O
. O

The O
learned O
counsel O
argued O
based O
on O
the O
Criminal B-LAW
Procedure I-LAW
Code I-LAW
. O

The O
bench O
comprising O
Justice B-PERSON
Priya I-PERSON
Singh I-PERSON
and O
Justice B-PERSON
Anil I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
reserved O
the O
order O
. O

The O
appeal O
arises O
from O
the O
judgment O
dated O
10th B-DATE
January I-DATE
2021 I-DATE
. O

The O
accused O
was O
charged O
under O
IPC B-LAW
Section I-LAW
420 I-LAW
. O

The O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
upheld O
the O
decision O
of O
the O
Madras B-ORG
High I-ORG
Court I-ORG
. O

The O
witness O
, O
Ms. B-PERSON
Sunita I-PERSON
Yadav I-PERSON
, O
was O
examined O
. O

The O
case O
titled O
" O
Ramesh B-PERSON
v. O
State B-ORG
of O
Uttar B-ORG
Pradesh I-ORG
" O
was O
relied O
upon O
. O

The O
bail O
application O
was O
listed O
for O
hearing O
on O
05-05-2023 B-DATE
. O

The O
respondent O
, O
M/s. B-ORG
ABC I-ORG
Ltd. I-ORG
, O
contested O
the O
claim O
. O

The O
arbitration O
award O
was O
passed O
under O
the O
Arbitration B-LAW
and I-LAW
Conciliation I-LAW
Act I-LAW
, O
1996 B-DATE
. O

The O
complainant O
filed O
a O
case O
under O
the O
Negotiable B-LAW
Instruments I-LAW
Act I-LAW
. O

Justice B-PERSON
Deepak B-PERSON
Misra I-PERSON
read O
the O
operative O
portion O
. O

The O
landmark O
case O
of O
Kesavananda B-PERSON
Bharati I-PERSON
v. O
State B-ORG
of O
Kerala I-ORG
was O
discussed O
. O

The O
special O
leave O
petition O
was O
numbered O
as O
SLP B-CASE
( O
Crl O
) O
No. I-CASE
5546 I-CASE
of O
2023 B-DATE
. O

The O
defense O
cited O
the O
doctrine O
of O
basic O
structure O
. O

The O
matter O
was O
adjourned O
to O
12th B-DATE
September I-DATE
, O
2024 I-DATE
. O

The O
deposition O
of O
PW O
- O
1 O
, O
Shri B-PERSON
Vijay I-PERSON
Kumar I-PERSON
, O
was O
recorded O
. O

The O
court O
interpreted O
Section B-LAW
438 I-LAW
CrPC I-LAW
. O

The O
respondent O
is O
the O
State B-ORG
of O
Maharashtra I-ORG
. O

The O
judge O
referred O
to O
the O
principles O
in O
Maneka B-PERSON
Gandhi I-PERSON
v. O
Union B-ORG
of I-ORG
India I-ORG
. O

The O
order O
was O
pronounced O
in O
open O
court O
. O

The O
legal O
heir O
, O
Smt. B-PERSON
Laxmi I-PERSON
Devi I-PERSON
, O
was O
impleaded O
. O

The O
writ O
petition O
under O
Article B-LAW
226 I-LAW
was O
allowed O
. O

The O
accused O
was O
acquitted O
of O
all O
charges O
. O

The O
compensation O
was O
awarded O
under O
Section B-LAW
357 I-LAW
CrPC I-LAW
. O

The O
testimony O
of O
the O
investigating O
officer O
was O
crucial O
. O

The O
case O
diary O
was O
summoned O
. O

The O
complainant O
alleged O
cheating O
under O
Section B-LAW
420 I-LAW
IPC I-LAW
. O

The O
cross O
examination O
was O
deferred O
. O

The O
document O
was O
marked O
as O
Exhibit O
A O
. O

The O
defense O
counsel O
, O
Mr. B-PERSON
Jain I-PERSON
, O
objected O
. O

The O
evidence O
act O
, O
1872 B-DATE
, O
was O
applicable O
. O

The O
firm O
, O
M/s. B-ORG
Gupta I-ORG
& I-ORG
Sons I-ORG
, O
was O
a O
party O
. O

The O
government O
pleader O
appeared O
for O
the O
state O
. O

The O
hon'ble O
court O
granted O
interim O
relief O
. O

The O
impugned O
order O
was O
set O
aside O
. O

The O
judicial O
magistrate O
issued O
summons O
. O

The O
land O
acquisition O
reference O
was O
decided O
. O

The O
memo O
of O
appeal O
was O
filed O
belatedly O
. O

The O
non O
- O
applicant O
did O
not O
appear O
. O

The O
objection O
petition O
was O
overruled O
. O

The O
plaintiff O
examined O
three O
witnesses O
. O

The O
quashment O
petition O
under O
Section B-LAW
482 I-LAW
CrPC I-LAW
was O
dismissed O
. O

The O
revision O
petition O
was O
allowed O
. O

The O
sale O
deed O
was O
executed O
on O
23-11-2019 B-DATE
. O

The O
tenancy O
rights O
were O
protected O
under O
the O
Rent B-LAW
Control I-LAW
Act I-LAW
. O

The O
unregistered O
document O
was O
inadmissible O
. O

The O
verdict O
was O
unanimous O
. O

The O
witness O
turned O
hostile O
. O

The O
youth O
was O
tried O
as O
an O
adult O
. O

The O
zonal O
manager O
deposed O
. O

An O
application O
under O
Order B-LAW
VII I-LAW
Rule I-LAW
11 I-LAW
CPC I-LAW
was O
filed O
. O

By O
the O
order O
dated O
1st B-DATE
April I-DATE
, O
2023 I-DATE
, O
the O
bail O
was O
granted O
. O

Can O
the O
evidence O
be O
reexamined O
? O

During O
the O
pendency O
of O
the O
suit O
, O
the O
applicant O
died O
. O

Each O
party O
shall O
bear O
its O
own O
costs O
. O

For O
the O
reasons O
stated O
above O
, O
the O
appeal O
is O
dismissed O
. O

Grant O
of O
probation O
was O
sought O
under O
the O
Probation B-LAW
of I-LAW
Offenders I-LAW
Act I-LAW
. O

He O
was O
convicted O
under O
the O
NDPS B-LAW
Act I-LAW
. O

In O
the O
facts O
and O
circumstances O
of O
the O
case O
, O
we O
find O
no O
merit O
. O

It O
is O
a O
fit O
case O
for O
interference O
under O
Article B-LAW
136 I-LAW
. O

Judgment O
and O
order O
are O
upheld O
. O

Leave O
granted O
. O

Let O
a O
copy O
of O
this O
order O
be O
sent O
to O
the O
trial O
court O
. O

Maintainability O
of O
the O
petition O
was O
questioned O
. O

No O
further O
time O
shall O
be O
granted O
. O

On O
behalf O
of O
the O
appellant O
, O
Mr. B-PERSON
Kapoor I-PERSON
advanced O
arguments O
. O

Point O
is O
answered O
in O
the O
negative O
. O

Quantum O
of O
sentence O
was O
challenged O
. O

Respondent O
No. O
2 O
, O
Shri B-PERSON
Mehta I-PERSON
, O
supported O
the O
order O
. O

Service O
is O
complete O
. O

The O
ad O
interim O
injunction O
is O
made O
absolute O
. O

The O
affidavit O
of O
evidence O
was O
filed O
. O

The O
allegation O
of O
fabrication O
was O
not O
proved O
. O

The O
amending O
act O
of O
2015 B-DATE
was O
applicable O
. O

The O
anticipatory O
bail O
plea O
was O
rejected O
. O

The O
appellate O
court O
remanded O
the O
case O
. O

The O
applicability O
of O
the O
Limitation B-LAW
Act I-LAW
was O
considered O
. O

The O
award O
was O
set O
aside O
for O
patent O
illegality O
. O

The O
bank O
guarantee O
was O
invoked O
. O

The O
bar O
under O
Order B-LAW
II I-LAW
Rule I-LAW
2 I-LAW
CPC I-LAW
was O
pleaded O
. O

The O
benefit O
of O
doubt O
was O
extended O
. O

The O
cause O
title O
was O
amended O
. O

The O
charge O
was O
framed O
under O
Section B-LAW
306 I-LAW
IPC I-LAW
. O

The O
civil O
appeal O
arises O
out O
of O
SLP B-CASE
( O
C O
) O
No. I-CASE
2022 I-CASE
of O
2021 B-DATE
. O

The O
compounding O
application O
was O
allowed O
. O

The O
concept O
of O
equal O
pay O
for O
equal O
work O
was O
invoked O
. O

The O
confessional O
statement O
was O
retracted O
. O

The O
consent O
decree O
was O
passed O
. O

The O
contempt O
petition O
was O
dropped O
. O

The O
contract O
was O
governed O
by O
the O
Indian B-LAW
Contract I-LAW
Act I-LAW
. O

The O
costs O
were O
awarded O
to O
the O
successful O
party O
. O

The O
counter O
claim O
was O
dismissed O
. O

The O
court O
fee O
was O
deficient O
. O

The O
court O
noted O
the O
law O
laid O
down O
in O
Vishaka B-PERSON
v. O
State B-ORG
of O
Rajasthan I-ORG
. O

The O
criminal O
miscellaneous O
petition O
is O
disposed O
of O
. O

The O
cross O
objections O
were O
not O
pressed O
. O

The O
decree O
holder O
filed O
for O
execution O
. O

The O
default O
in O
appearance O
was O
condoned O
. O

The O
defense O
of O
alibi O
was O
established O
. O

The O
delay O
of O
150 B-DATE
days I-DATE
was O
condoned O
. O

The O
demand O
draft O
was O
produced O
. O

The O
department O
challenged O
the O
tribunal O
's O
order O
. O

The O
deposit O
was O
made O
within O
the O
stipulated O
time O
. O

The O
detenu O
was O
released O
. O

The O
disciplinary O
authority O
imposed O
the O
penalty O
. O

The O
discovery O
application O
was O
allowed O
. O

The O
discretion O
was O
exercised O
in O
favour O
of O
the O
accused O
. O

The O
dispute O
was O
referred O
to O
arbitration O
. O

The O
doctrine O
of O
estoppel O
was O
applicable O
. O

The O
document O
was O
not O
duly O
stamped O
. O

The O
easement O
rights O
were O
claimed O
. O

The O
election O
petition O
was O
dismissed O
for O
non O
- O
prosecution O
. O

The O
enquiry O
report O
was O
quashed O
. O

The O
ex O
parte O
order O
was O
set O
aside O
. O

The O
execution O
proceedings O
were O
stayed O
. O

The O
exemplary O
costs O
were O
imposed O
. O

The O
exhibit O
was O
taken O
on O
record O
. O

The O
expert O
opinion O
was O
relied O
upon O
. O

The O
fact O
in O
issue O
was O
not O
proved O
. O

The O
family O
court O
granted O
divorce O
. O

The O
federal O
structure O
was O
discussed O
. O

The O
fiduciary O
relationship O
was O
acknowledged O
. O

The O
final O
hearing O
commenced O
on O
03-10-2022 B-DATE
. O

The O
findings O
recorded O
by O
the O
trial O
court O
were O
perverse O
. O

The O
first O
information O
report O
was O
quashed O
. O

The O
forged O
document O
was O
detected O
. O

The O
garnishee O
order O
was O
passed O
. O

The O
government O
notification O
was O
challenged O
. O

The O
guardian O
ad O
litem O
was O
appointed O
. O

The O
hearing O
was O
conducted O
via O
video O
conferencing O
. O

The O
honorarium O
was O
paid O
as O
per O
rules O
. O

The O
illegal O
construction O
was O
demolished O
. O

The O
impugned O
judgment O
creates O
a O
precedent O
. O

The O
in O
camera O
proceedings O
were O
directed O
. O

The O
incidental O
proceedings O
were O
dropped O
. O

The O
injunction O
operated O
until O
further O
orders O
. O

The O
inquiry O
under O
Section B-LAW
202 I-LAW
CrPC I-LAW
was O
directed O
. O

The O
interlocutory O
application O
was O
disposed O
of O
. O

The O
interpretation O
of O
the O
statute O
was O
in O
question O
. O

The O
interrogatories O
were O
delivered O
. O

The O
investigation O
was O
transferred O
to O
the O
CBI B-ORG
. O

The O
judicial O
review O
was O
sought O
. O

The O
jurisdictional O
error O
was O
apparent O
. O

The O
juvenile O
was O
dealt O
with O
under O
the O
Juvenile B-LAW
Justice I-LAW
Act I-LAW
. O

The O
land O
records O
were O
summoned O
. O

The O
lease O
deed O
was O
registered O
on O
11-06-2018 B-DATE
. O

The O
legal O
representative O
was O
brought O
on O
record O
. O

The O
legislative O
intent O
was O
clarified O
. O

The O
liability O
was O
apportioned O
. O

The O
limitation O
period O
expired O
on O
31-12-2022 B-DATE
. O

The O
loan O
agreement O
was O
enforced O
. O

The O
locus O
standi O
of O
the O
petitioner O
was O
challenged O
. O

The O
magisterial O
inquiry O
was O
ordered O
. O

The O
main O
appeal O
is O
still O
pending O
. O

The O
maintainability O
objection O
was O
overruled O
. O

The O
mandatory O
injunction O
was O
granted O
. O

The O
medical O
negligence O
was O
alleged O
. O

The O
memorandum O
of O
understanding O
was O
violated O
. O

The O
mutation O
of O
the O
property O
was O
sanctioned O
. O

The O
natural O
justice O
principles O
were O
violated O
. O

The O
negotiation O
failed O
. O

The O
next O
date O
is O
fixed O
for O
arguments O
on O
charge O
. O

The O
non O
- O
obstante O
clause O
was O
interpreted O
. O

The O
notice O
under O
Section B-LAW
80 I-LAW
CPC I-LAW
was O
served O
. O

The O
objection O
regarding O
territorial O
jurisdiction O
was O
raised O
. O

The O
official O
liquidator O
was O
appointed O
. O

The O
omission O
was O
not O
fatal O
. O

The O
opinion O
of O
the O
full O
bench O
was O
sought O
. O

The O
oral O
evidence O
was O
concluded O
. O

The O
order O
of O
attachment O
was O
passed O
. O

The O
order O
sheet O
reflects O
the O
proceedings O
. O

The O
original O
records O
were O
summoned O
. O

The O
pardon O
was O
granted O
to O
the O
approver O
. O

The O
part O
compliance O
was O
noted O
. O

The O
patent O
infringement O
was O
alleged O
. O

The O
payment O
was O
made O
by O
cheque O
. O

The O
penal O
provision O
was O
invoked O
. O

The O
permission O
under O
Section B-LAW
197 I-LAW
CrPC I-LAW
was O
obtained O
. O

The O
permissive O
possession O
was O
accepted O
. O

The O
plaint O
was O
returned O
for O
presentation O
to O
the O
proper O
court O
. O

The O
plea O
of O
autrefois O
acquit O
was O
rejected O
. O

The O
possession O
certificate O
was O
filed O
. O

The O
power O
of O
attorney O
was O
executed O
. O

The O
prayer O
for O
interim O
relief O
was O
rejected O
. O

The O
pre O
- O
emption O
right O
was O
upheld O
. O

The O
precedent O
was O
distinguished O
on O
facts O
. O

The O
preliminary O
decree O
was O
passed O
. O

The O
prima O
facie O
case O
was O
made O
out O
. O

The O
principal O
judge O
, O
City B-ORG
Civil I-ORG
Court I-ORG
, O
allowed O
the O
application O
. O

The O
private O
complaint O
was O
dismissed O
. O

The O
privileged O
communication O
was O
protected O
. O

The O
probate O
was O
granted O
. O

The O
procedural O
lapse O
was O
condoned O
. O

The O
proclamation O
under O
Section B-LAW
82 I-LAW
CrPC I-LAW
was O
issued O
. O

The O
producer O
company O
was O
impleaded O
as O
a O
party O
. O

The O
promissory O
estoppel O
was O
pleaded O
. O

The O
proper O
stamp O
duty O
was O
paid O
. O

The O
proportional O
relief O
was O
granted O
. O

The O
proposed O
amendment O
was O
disallowed O
. O

The O
prosecution O
sanction O
was O
invalid O
. O

The O
prospective O
overruling O
was O
applied O
. O

The O
proximate O
cause O
was O
established O
. O

The O
public O
interest O
litigation O
was O
admitted O
. O

The O
punitive O
damages O
were O
awarded O
. O

The O
purchase O
agreement O
was O
specifically O
enforced O
. O

The O
question O
of O
law O
was O
referred O
to O
the O
larger O
bench O
. O

The O
ratification O
was O
proved O
. O

The O
re O
- O
assessment O
order O
was O
set O
aside O
. O

The O
re O
- O
examination O
was O
permitted O
. O

The O
rebuttal O
evidence O
was O
closed O
. O

The O
recall O
application O
was O
allowed O
. O

The O
recording O
of O
evidence O
was O
completed O
. O

The O
recovery O
suit O
was O
decreed O
. O

The O
reference O
was O
answered O
against O
the O
department O
. O

The O
registered O
sale O
deed O
was O
exhibited O
. O

The O
rejection O
order O
was O
communicated O
. O

The O
rejoinder O
affidavit O
was O
filed O
. O

The O
relied O
upon O
documents O
were O
marked O
. O

The O
remedy O
of O
appeal O
was O
available O
. O

The O
replication O
was O
filed O
by O
the O
plaintiff O
. O

The O
report O
of O
the O
local O
commissioner O
was O
accepted O
. O

The O
revision O
application O
was O
dismissed O
as O
withdrawn O
. O

The O
right O
to O
privacy O
was O
invoked O
. O

The O
rule O
of O
ejusdem O
generis O
was O
applied O
. O

The O
sale O
was O
confirmed O
by O
the O
court O
. O

The O
sanction O
for O
prosecution O
was O
granted O
. O

The O
search O
and O
seizure O
was O
conduct O
. O

The O
second O
appeal O
was O
admitted O
on O
substantial O
questions O
of O
law O
. O

The O
security O
deposit O
was O
forfeited O
. O

The O
seizure O
memo O
was O
proved O
. O

The O
select O
list O
was O
quashed O
. O

The O
sentencing O
policy O
was O
discussed O
. O

The O
show O
cause O
notice O
was O
issued O
. O

The O
signed O
copy O
of O
the O
order O
was O
placed O
on O
record O
. O

The O
specific O
performance O
suit O
was O
decreed O
. O

The O
stay O
petition O
was O
dismissed O
. O

The O
stipulated O
time O
was O
extended O
. O

The O
sub O
- O
registrar O
was O
made O
a O
party O
. O

The O
subsequent O
event O
was O
taken O
into O
consideration O
. O

The O
substantial O
question O
of O
law O
was O
framed O
. O

The O
succession O
certificate O
was O
granted O
. O

The O
summary O
suit O
was O
instituted O
. O

The O
summons O
were O
served O
by O
substituted O
service O
. O

The O
supplementary O
affidavit O
was O
taken O
on O
record O
. O

The O
surety O
bond O
was O
furnished O
. O

The O
suspension O
order O
was O
revoked O
. O

The O
tariff O
rates O
were O
challenged O
. O

The O
tax O
demand O
was O
stayed O
. O

The O
tenancy O
was O
protected O
under O
the O
state O
act O
. O

The O
termination O
order O
was O
held O
to O
be O
illegal O
. O

The O
test O
identification O
parade O
was O
conducted O
. O

The O
time O
barred O
application O
was O
rejected O
. O

The O
title O
suit O
was O
decreed O
. O

The O
transfer O
petition O
was O
allowed O
. O

The O
trespass O
was O
proved O
. O

The O
tribunal O
upheld O
the O
order O
of O
the O
commissioner O
. O

The O
undue O
influence O
was O
alleged O
. O

The O
unregistered O
firm O
was O
sued O
. O

The O
validity O
of O
the O
bye O
- O
law O
was O
upheld O
. O

The O
verification O
of O
the O
pleadings O
was O
defective O
. O

The O
veto O
power O
was O
discussed O
. O

The O
waiver O
was O
expressly O
made O
. O

The O
warranty O
deed O
was O
executed O
. O

The O
will O
was O
probated O
. O

The O
withdrawal O
of O
the O
prosecution O
was O
permitted O
. O

The O
witness O
was O
declared O
hostile O
. O

The O
writ O
jurisdiction O
was O
invoked O
. O

The O
wrongful O
dismissal O
was O
challenged O
. O

This O
concludes O
the O
list O
of O
400 O
sentences O
. O

